<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<XML_DIZ_INFO>
  <MASTER_PAD_VERSION_INFO>
    <MASTER_PAD_VERSION>4.0</MASTER_PAD_VERSION>
    <MASTER_PAD_INFO>Portable Application Description, or PAD for short, is a data set that is used by shareware authors to disseminate information to anyone interested in their software products. To find out more go to http://pad.asp-software.org</MASTER_PAD_INFO>
  </MASTER_PAD_VERSION_INFO>

  <Company_Info>
    <Company_Name>JSTools</Company_Name>
    <Address_1></Address_1>
    <Address_2></Address_2>
    <City_Town></City_Town>
    <State_Province></State_Province>
    <Zip_Postal_Code></Zip_Postal_Code>
    <Country>Israel</Country>
    <Company_WebSite_URL>https://github.com/jstoolsspace/JSON-Studio</Company_WebSite_URL>
    <Contact_Info>
      <Author_First_Name>Anton</Author_First_Name>
      <Author_Last_Name>Liberant</Author_Last_Name>
      <Author_Email>anliberant@gmail.com</Author_Email>
      <Contact_First_Name>Anton</Contact_First_Name>
      <Contact_Last_Name>Liberant</Contact_Last_Name>
      <Contact_Email>anliberant@gmail.com</Contact_Email>
    </Contact_Info>
    <Support_Info>
      <Sales_Email>anliberant@gmail.com</Sales_Email>
      <Support_Email>anliberant@gmail.com</Support_Email>
      <General_Email>anliberant@gmail.com</General_Email>
      <Sales_Phone></Sales_Phone>
      <Support_Phone></Support_Phone>
      <General_Phone></General_Phone>
      <Fax_Phone></Fax_Phone>
    </Support_Info>
  </Company_Info>

  <Program_Info>
    <Program_Name>JSON Studio</Program_Name>
    <Program_Version>1.0.5</Program_Version>
    <Program_Release_Month>06</Program_Release_Month>
    <Program_Release_Day>28</Program_Release_Day>
    <Program_Release_Year>2026</Program_Release_Year>
    <Program_Cost_Dollars>0.00</Program_Cost_Dollars>
    <Program_Cost_Other_Code>USD</Program_Cost_Other_Code>
    <Program_Cost_Other>0.00</Program_Cost_Other>
    <Program_Type>Freeware</Program_Type>
    <Program_Release_Status>New Release</Program_Release_Status>
    <Program_Install_Support>Install and Uninstall</Program_Install_Support>
    <Program_OS_Support>Win11,Win10,Win10 x64,Win8 x64,Win8,Win7 x64,Win7,WinVista,Mac OS X,Mac Other,Linux,Linux Console,Linux Gnome,Linux GPL,Linux Open Source</Program_OS_Support>
    <Program_Language>English</Program_Language>
    <Program_Change_Info>Adds a portable Windows build (no install; settings kept beside the executable). Includes lossless tree/raw/search/JSONPath/diff/JSONL views, base64 image preview, jump-to-node, format/minify/export and a node detail panel.</Program_Change_Info>
    <Program_Specific_Category>Development</Program_Specific_Category>
    <Program_Categories>Development::Other</Program_Categories>
    <Program_System_Requirements>Windows 10/11 (64-bit), macOS 11+, or 64-bit Linux. 4 GB RAM, ~150 MB disk. Edge WebView2 runtime on Windows (preinstalled on Win10/11).</Program_System_Requirements>
    <File_Info>
      <File_Size_Bytes>2653019</File_Size_Bytes>
      <File_Size_K>2591</File_Size_K>
      <File_Size_MB>2.53</File_Size_MB>
    </File_Info>
    <Expire_Info>
      <Has_Expire_Info>N</Has_Expire_Info>
      <Expire_Count></Expire_Count>
      <Expire_Based_On></Expire_Based_On>
      <Expire_Other_Info></Expire_Other_Info>
      <Expire_Month></Expire_Month>
      <Expire_Day></Expire_Day>
      <Expire_Year></Expire_Year>
    </Expire_Info>
  </Program_Info>

  <Program_Descriptions>
    <English>
      <Keywords>JSON, JSON viewer, JSON editor, JSONL, NDJSON, JSONPath, JSON diff, JSON formatter, lossless, offline, developer tools</Keywords>
      <Char_Desc_45>Private, lossless desktop JSON workspace</Char_Desc_45>
      <Char_Desc_80>Fast, private desktop app to explore, search, query and diff large JSON files.</Char_Desc_80>
      <Char_Desc_250>JSON Studio is a private, lossless desktop app for large JSON. Open files up to 500 MB, browse them as a fast tree, search, run JSONPath queries, diff two documents and view JSONL tables - all 100% locally with no uploads, accounts or telemetry.</Char_Desc_250>
      <Char_Desc_450>JSON Studio is a private, lossless desktop workspace for large JSON. It opens files up to 500 MB instantly and preserves your data exactly - big integers, high-precision decimals, key order and the original bytes are never altered. Browse a virtualized tree, search keys and values, run RFC 9535 JSONPath queries, structurally diff two documents, view JSONL/NDJSON tables and preview base64 images. Everything runs on your machine: no network, no accounts, no telemetry.</Char_Desc_450>
      <Char_Desc_2000>JSON Studio is a private, lossless workspace for JSON.

Most JSON tools either choke on big files, silently mangle your numbers, or send your data to a server. JSON Studio does none of that. It is a native desktop app built for speed and correctness: open a half-gigabyte file and start navigating immediately, knowing that what you see is byte-for-byte what is on disk. Everything runs on your own machine - no accounts, no uploads, no analytics, no network calls - making it safe for proprietary, regulated or personal data.

What you can do:
- Browse huge files smoothly with a virtualized tree and raw view that stay responsive on documents up to 500 MB, with collapse/expand, expand-to-depth, type and item-count badges and full keyboard navigation.
- Trust your data: big integers, high-precision decimals, key order and the exact original text are preserved losslessly - nothing is rounded, reordered or reformatted.
- Find anything fast: search across keys and values with case sensitivity, whole-field matching, regular expressions and subtree scoping, then jump straight to a match in the tree.
- Query with JSONPath: run RFC 9535 expressions with per-document history, execution timing, result counts and export to JSON or JSONL.
- Compare two documents with a structural diff (key order ignored) that matches arrays by index or by a key field and highlights what was added, removed or changed.
- Work with JSONL / NDJSON as a virtualized table with selectable columns, field statistics and invalid-row highlighting.
- Preview embedded images: string values that are data:image URIs or base64 (PNG, JPEG, GIF, WebP, SVG) can be viewed inline.
- Format and export: copy pretty-printed or minified JSON, or save the re-serialized document in one click.
- Stay in flow with tabs, remembered sessions, live reload when a file changes on disk, a node detail panel with copyable path and value, and System/Light/Dark themes.

A portable Windows build is also available: it runs without installation and keeps its settings beside the executable. JSON Studio is free and open source (MIT) and available for Windows, macOS and Linux.</Char_Desc_2000>
    </English>
  </Program_Descriptions>

  <Web_Info>
    <Application_URLs>
      <Application_Info_URL>https://github.com/jstoolsspace/JSON-Studio</Application_Info_URL>
      <Application_Order_URL>https://github.com/jstoolsspace/JSON-Studio/releases/latest</Application_Order_URL>
      <Application_Screenshot_URL>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jstoolsspace/JSON-Studio/main/docs/screenshot.png</Application_Screenshot_URL>
      <Application_Icon_URL>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jstoolsspace/JSON-Studio/main/brand/logo-256.png</Application_Icon_URL>
      <Application_XML_File_URL>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jstoolsspace/JSON-Studio/main/pad_file.xml</Application_XML_File_URL>
    </Application_URLs>
    <Download_URLs>
      <Primary_Download_URL>https://github.com/jstoolsspace/JSON-Studio/releases/download/v1.0.5/JSON.Studio_1.0.5_x64-setup.exe</Primary_Download_URL>
      <Secondary_Download_URL>https://github.com/jstoolsspace/JSON-Studio/releases/download/v1.0.5/JSON.Studio_1.0.5_x64_en-US.msi</Secondary_Download_URL>
      <Additional_Download_URL_1>https://github.com/jstoolsspace/JSON-Studio/releases/download/v1.0.5/JSON-Studio-1.0.5-portable-x64.zip</Additional_Download_URL_1>
      <Additional_Download_URL_2>https://github.com/jstoolsspace/JSON-Studio/releases/latest</Additional_Download_URL_2>
    </Download_URLs>
  </Web_Info>
</XML_DIZ_INFO>
